

Portland OF

□ | ■ hiranmayi.duvvuri@gmail.com | ★ hiranmayiduvvuri.com | • hrmyd

Summary _

Currently an **Data Scientist** at Vacasa in Portland, OR. I have 3+ years working in data analytics and research in various aspects for both business and science. I am comfortable jumping into unfamiliar projects and learning new skillsets along the way. I have experience working with a fledgling data science team and communicating to both non-technical stakeholders and engineers alike.

Skills

Programming Python, PostgreSQL, Git, Bash

Data SciencePandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Keras, Data Visualization, Feature Engineering/ETL, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Predictive

Modeling, Machine Learning, Image Processing, Documentation

Experience _____

Vacasa Portland, OR

DATA SCIENTIST Jul 2018 - PRESENT

- Presenting data to various stakeholders and working with engineers to productionize models.
- · Created updated model predicting home cleaning times, greatly improving error rate with an ROI of \$3.4m
- Led feature engineering side of data lake project to provide central source of features among both the data science team and rest of the company. Main goal was to reduce duplicate efforts among the team and increase knowledge sharing.
- Put together reports for product on how models worked, affect of adding or removing features, and exploratory data analysis (EDA) results.
- Presenting work outside of the team and documentation for internal products.

ANALYST Sep 2017 - Jul 2018

• Created a churn model using machine learning methods and python. Used this opportunity to develop my skills in stats, machine learning, SQL, and the use of python for data science.

Part of this was also identifying gaps in owner data, any new data that could be acquired to further help with the model, as well as indicators to help determine at risk owners.

• Presented work to COO and other upper management to show current status of project and working hands on with the direction of the model.

University of Oregon - Institute of Molecular Biology

Eugene, OR

BIOINFORMATICIST - SELKER LAB

Oct 2016 - May 2017

- Updated and managed scripts for analysis of ChIP-seq and RNA-seq data.
- Compared ChIP-seq datasets looking at differences in RNA pol II binding between different strains of n. crassa. Done using various data analysis programs and automated using R and bash scripting.

SCIENTIFIC PROGRAMMER - HARMS LAB

Sep 2015 - May 2017

- Developed a GUI using PyQt5 for python API that analyses isothermal calorimetry (ITC) data. Along with this, wrote documentation for GUI using sphinx on Read the Docs as well as a C extension to calculate the binding polynomial in the API.

 Repo: https://github.com/harmslab/pytc-gui and https://github.com/harmslab/pytc
- Developed an extension of a phage display analysis pipeline. Researched and implemented different methods of data clustering. Repo: https://github.com/harmslab/phagedisplay

Publications

Hiranmayi Duvvuri, Lucas C. Wheeler, and Michael J. Harms

Biochemistry

PYTC: OPEN-SOURCE PYTHON SOFTWARE FOR GLOBAL ANALYSES OF ISOTHERMAL TITRATION CALORIMETRY DATA

2018

Education

University of Oregon

Eugene, OR

Sep 2011 - Sep 2016

B.S. IN BIOCHEMISTRY

• focus on biology, chemistry, and computer science